<p>
    <strong>OM&amp;IS 324 Group Project - Written Report</strong>
</p>
<center> <strong>Baseball Team Analysis</strong> </center>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        
	<img
            width="625"
            height="322"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image002.jpg"
            alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/r10nvO7N2BGPp7lvSKEb57sXN7q7NOhlHgRv8IU0zqhszTSzAV1wkd0NZnEDYDKwW8fh8zVuv8PdVJXKXXgM3sjpIlXXq08Uc7e148YLHjMQZLiGhLdRwaITjy6VdiFhmT2VI-_E"
        />
    </strong>
   
</p>
<p align="center">
    2014-2015
</p>
<p align="center">
    <em>STATISTICAL TESTING AND VISUALIZATION CREATED IN EXCEL AND TABLEAU</em>
</p>
<p align="center">
    Cameron Thomas, Dakota Gannon, Mark Van Wormer, Kyle Jensen | OM&amp;IS 324
    | Fall 2018
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Introduction:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    <a name="_Hlk531727184">
        For our project we are examining Major League Baseball statistics from
        2014-2015 that were sourced from <u>Kaggle.com</u>. We will be
        investigating correlations between teams wins while considering other
        variables. The resources we are using to examine the data are Tableau
        and Excel. This is to assist in visualizing the data using graphs and
        charts, as well as performing regression analysis on the data set.
    </a>
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Purpose:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    The purpose of our project is to compare our dependent variable which is
    wins and compare them against other variables, such as attendance and runs
    allowed. We also want to find out if other variables have an effect on
    wins. Our goal as we examined this dataset ultimately is to figure out what
    variables have an impact on wins. We will determine our goals by utilizing
    graphs, statistical measures, regression, and hypothesis testing.
    Furthermore, we will analyze the various results of the visuals and the
    statistical analyses to determine our overall recommendations and
    conclusions on how teams are winning, how to increase team’s overall wins,
    and teams’ popularities
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Description of the Dataset:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    As stated above, our dataset is comprised of multiple stats from major
    league baseball teams during 2014 and 2015. The dataset we will be
    analyzing has a total of 48 variables. We found it easier to divide the
    variables into offensive and defensive statistics. The offensive variables
    we thought would have the most potential effect on wins are: hits, 2b, 3b,
    and homeruns. Hits are described as how often a team hits the ball and gets
    on base. We are using the abbreviations 2b and 3b to describe doubles and
    triples, which is how often a team gets a hit and makes it to second and
    third base respectively. It would make sense that these variables have a
    strong impact on wins because a team should be more likely to win if they
    have more opportunities on base, which may lead to more runs scored.
</p>
<p>
    The defensive variables we thought would have the most effect on wins are
    hits allowed, runs allowed, and earned runs. If a team has a high number of
    hits allowed and a low number of earned runs, then we believe that the team
    would have a high number of wins. We also hypothesized that if a team does
    not allow many hits, walks, and runs, then they would have a better chance
    of winning more often.
</p>
<p>
    We did an initial analysis of descriptive measures for team wins in each of
    the years. The table can be seen below. We found that wins are normally
    distributed with a slight positive skewed and a wide degree of dispersion
    (kurtosis). Mean, standard deviation, and variance do not seem to differ
    too much from year to year.
</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="624">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td valign="top">
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    Mean
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    Standard Deviation
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    Variance
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    Skewness
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    Kurtosis
                </p>
            </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    2014
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    81
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    9.44
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    89.07
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    0.02
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    -1.01
                </p>
            </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    2015
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    80.97
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    10.28
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    105.63
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    0.04
                </p>
            </td>
            <td valign="top">
                <p>
                    -0.87
                </p>
            </td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Possible Relationships for Wins:</strong>
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong></strong>
</p>
<p>
    The baseball team data for years 2014 and 2015 have various variables that
    could potentially correlate with team/franchise wins, such as different
    types of hits, overall hits, hits allowed, and many more. However, not all
    the variables within this dataset fit our overall goals and purposes. For
    example, the dataset contains repetitive nominal data that are qualitative,
    such as variables for franchise, team, and retro. Therefore, sticking with
    variables and attributes that are numerical and discrete will allows us to
    further our analyses on different impactors of team/franchise wins. In
    addition, to fit the scope of the project, we will be correlating 5
    different variables for wins. We will begin with comparing offensive
    variables/stats of different teams to see if there is actual statistical
    evidence that shows the reason why teams are winning. A great variable to
    begin with would be the total hits of each team. Through hypothesis
    testing, if there is a linear relationship that appears for hits and wins,
    then we will further our analysis on different types of hits; such as
    double hits, triple hits, and homeruns. The next goal for our analysis will
    be to investigate defensive variables/stats. We will instigate hits allowed
    and then further our analysis with other defensive variables/stats, such as
    runs allowed and earned runs. Lastly, we will determine if there is any
    relation between overall attendance and wins.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Descriptive Statistical Analysis:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    Each variable correlation for wins that will be covered will explain and
    show linear regression hypothesis testing through tools in Excel. Utilizing
    scatter charts with linear trend lines and the regression/ANOVA tool for
    R-squared and p-value identification will demonstrate and determine the
    results of our overall analysis of impactors for wins. Furthermore, we will
    be assuming that the null hypothesis (H0: β1 = 0) for the linear regression
    stays true for all variable comparisons for wins, while rejecting the
    alternative hypothesis (H1: β1 ≠ 0).
</p>
<p>
    <strong>Hits Vs. Wins:</strong>
    <strong>
        <img
            width="590"
            height="227"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image004.jpg"
            alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/H1VEZDxKcFMCWKiGaG14vbR35E1pCQ2-t1vcUj62RkKVQcn_XkKHlEplicqHARqA4kduMmR3VUeb3Jt3OxavtWHrTaHCF67LVuAKdGEISKHMRM2UfMA_uj46LhCchdynKfjqbGb1"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="413"
            height="286"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image005.png"
            alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FbtEa58RdX5upiXiJ2JWs7HPohO46jaWc4RWmQGOxoquKXEjAH--G8eG_0H9ndk-spZDhNy_FIl4YnVzgB-TJX2SxeVCU7zueedpmkA8bfBzdgpGirkecS1ditLsNuVrDZ_mdx54"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    Analyzing the scatter chart and the regression/ANOVA output shows there to
    be an extremely weak linear relationship if any at all. The R-squared in
    the summary output shows to be at .0288, which is extremely low when
    comparing the 0-1 scale for R-squared. This shows that the goodness-of-fit
    is extremely poor, with almost no variability of the response data around
    its mean. Also, an example from the dataset shows that in year 2014,
    Seattle Mariners had 87 wins and 1328 hits while Tampa Bay Rays had 77 wins
    and 1361 hits. There are many other teams with similar outcomes and this
    shows why the goodness-of-fit is poor. This also shows why offensive
    variables/stats are a bad predictor and impactor for wins as many other
    similar variables have the same outcomes. Next, the p-value (Significance
    F) is surprisingly high. The p-value is at .1951, which is significantly
    higher than .05. When checking the p-value for the hypothesis testing, 1951
    &lt; .05 is not true, therefore the null hypothesis is not rejected. The
    alternative shows to be not true, and then therefore, there is not a linear
    relationship between hits and wins. Ultimately, this shows offensive
    variables/stats of different teams have little to no impact when it comes
    to wins. This information also shows that there’s no reason to further our
    analysis with other offensive variables/stats, such as double hits, triples
    hits, and home-runs since the variables/stats have a high variability. For
    a double hits example, in year 2014, the Baltimore Orioles had 264 double
    hits and 96 wins while the San Diego Padres had 260 double hits with 74
    wins. Triple hits and home-runs also have similar outcomes.
</p>
<p>
    <strong>Hits Allowed Vs. Wins:</strong>
    <strong>
        <img
            width="590"
            height="358"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image006.png"
            alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Cl50_QwRMZoZkYbuj2d8NEnYJr7ltCeoc32rEtVHZMF85tcEsAuwDOFiTd_ua8TnBF0NMPqlyirMmGZDKRXO_ePhyqaUjl48t15mlAP9pWPdh5fi6cIulRaxGUSn_YDoEyR8WM3G"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="416"
            height="254"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image007.png"
            alt="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/3FbFvos_YuXbjc-jjiRqxgm44BvTFiCOAxsnE84IdfdihI1oG3iNSG0SDSf96QAwIYSytybK8_Qsh8EnKFrQP_83J4EgudN2LVLCDAoPjgtiwvcr_xsbxB59k_-fuGHfZzMQCEbB"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    The first defensive variable/stat shows there to be a negative linear
    relationship with y = -0.0724x + 182.05. This result makes sense because
    teams with higher number of wins allow less hits for the opposing team. For
    example, in year 2015, the St. Louis Cardinals had 100 wins with only 1359
    hits allowed. Also, in the same year the Philadelphia Phillies had the
    highest hits allowed at 1592 with 63 wins. They happen to be the team with
    the lowest number of wins throughout the MLB. Furthermore, this
    demonstration has a decent goodness-of-fit since the R-squared is at .3488
    and shows that some variability of the response is around its mean. Next,
    the p-value is shown to be extremely low and is evidently under .05.
    Therefore, the null hypothesis is rejected and shows that there is an
    existing linear relationship between these variables. Having an adequate
    goodness-to-fit and proof of significance of there being a linear
    relationship shows that hits allowed for teams is a good predictor and
    impactor for overall wins in the MLB.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Runs Allowed Vs. Wins:</strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="590"
            height="293"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image008.png"
            alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/kgCMe_zpGyPW-NQSgGTnCjkexpwflwArxHNGW513cCxBigZ-8g7rqycIB0dd8p65W2WD7L7uMm7wR0ApSyTR91R-_Sl3L0M8nCEiBJpTMZ_4fB7YcVepUmcYfC_DUjsAxJMFIb6n"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="414"
            height="208"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image009.png"
            alt="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/iiD-QnVHOjtdEe-MKxrMfUIrKVXs0DzdSLVunflJrdoAL3nG0wq0phMFG8hba3PW6dGR7QOW8AXUW_Tp_E5Ery1Pab6yfQOcrMw53ms5VaOldoMNXgdXpVAWB-gmlryWiJvjgdwe"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    This statistical analysis is similar to Hits Allowed Vs. Wins as it’s
    another negative linear regression (y = -0.1047x + 151.47). A team with
    lower runs allowed tend to win more baseball games. This regression has
    another decently high R-squared, which is at .573. The trend line in the
    scatter chart demonstrates that this statistical test has a good fit with
    the wins and runs allowed. The p-value in this demonstration is also well
    below .05. Therefore, the null hypothesis is rejected and shows that there
    is an existing linear relationship between these variables. Lastly, the
    goodness-of-fit and acceptance of the alternative hypothesis shows that
    this demonstration is a good predictor for wins.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Earned Runs Vs. Wins:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    <strong>
        <img
            width="586"
            height="256"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image011.jpg"
            alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lDNC9a56YLtItrSxWOnu7iqo7cppl1H2B7zbf0ryt5eps1CMowrZO3KObEZoEJR7mhDhJe5RCgr1gEhuNm21z8fJlaJj12-E6ZvslqMhUxTCiRxB322_CKvpqHxyZczZy2kxseLv"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="414"
            height="264"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image012.png"
            alt="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/hX6fp6LZ0sv_lFJssud9cOt-UbHssm1cYc9l3JW__HfIF9cpkuu9b0FuKnlMUq-uEch6jha11_IoR_8O2eS8QV7UMq_b_0hnQa8RgIiB6DDNjy5OPXYl-NAP8Kqm2fRmz3QvNYy2"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    Clarification of what earned runs are: It’s any run that scored against a
    pitcher without the benefit of an error, so therefore it’s a defensive
    variable/stat. Once again, the linear equation is negative (y = -5.2276x +
    1043). All defensive variables/stats should be negatively linear due to the
    dependent and independent variables having an inverse relationship between
    the two. This last statistical test for defensive variables/stats also
    shows to have a goodness-of-fit due to the R-squared being .5562.
    Ultimately, Runs Allowed Vs. Wins and Earned Runs Vs. Wins show to have a
    lot of variability of the response data around its mean. Also, the p-value
    for this test is once again significantly below .05, then therefore we
    reject the null hypothesis and accept the alternative hypothesis that shows
    there’s a linear relationship between the two variables. Earned runs shows
    to be a good predictor due to a high R-squared and proven linear regression
    through hypothesis testing.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Attendance Vs. Wins:</strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="586"
            height="357"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image013.png"
            alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0zuwoVoglgvT4Ao3luGPOcvlR1snD-39wlAstiEkCjeaXBI_BUzKtnLcaeybpL4qiyP491rtcZ8txvky4GuZYbioIPxgtf0qMH321cPh9ChZB0M_CYLgrqdtM_6cKK18HsnEH9hz"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p align="center">
    <strong>
        <img
            width="415"
            height="287"
            src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image014.png"
            alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/BbJMwZpIWzXoInghCMBh0L-bcZDagfiOnKoKyfvpRigmu2ZLWNqasc_m6Xat7pCtwv5OFarc8Ohs_eYCSE7bMTd1dswWU16JjX_k1ld5GbWqw8h7QjlihFUovYMmqQTtoV5xpUGz"
        />
    </strong>
</p>
<p>
    The last statistical analysis that is looked at is Attendance Vs. Wins. The
    R-squared in this test also seems to be low, which has evidently impacted
    the goodness-to-fit for the graph. Next, the p-value for this example is
    significantly low and below .05. The null hypothesis is once again
    rejected, and the alternative hypothesis is approved and therefore is shown
    to have significance and a linear relationship. By looking at the
    evidential information, attendance for a ballpark does increase with higher
    number of wins in a franchise.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Recommendations:</strong>
</p>
<p>
    Baseball teams can be split into two separate categories; offense and
    defense. For our analysis the focus was on which is more important to earn
    wins for the team. Does having a weak defense but a strong offense offer a
    better chance at winning more games, or does a strong defense but a weak
    offense offer a better opportunity? In this section we are focusing on the
    offensive stats recommendation, the defensive stats recommendations and
    then the most important non-game stat for teams, the attendance for the
    games.
</p>
<p>
    Our analysis found that there is no significant relationship amongst hits
    and wins. Furthermore, if there was conclusive evidence, then there’s an
    extremely weak goodness-of-fit that shows to be extremely poor with no
    variability. As mentioned earlier, in 2014, the Rays got 33 more hits
    during the season over the Mariners (the Mariners had 10 more wins). This
    shows that recommendations for teams do not concentrate solely on hits as
    they do not, at least statistically, mean a greater chance of winning. The
    reason that the other offensive variables vs wins wasn’t included was
    because they didn’t have a significant enough impact on the data.
</p>
<p>
    Having a strong offense that includes hits, 1B, 2B, 3B, and runs does not
    mean a team can always win as there is not a high correlation between them
    as visualized below. Also, we noticed that the top three and bottom three
    teams with the highest hits in 2014 and 2015 did not necessarily have the
    highest or lowest number of wins. For example, STL had the highest number
    of wins in 2015 but did not have the highest number of hits (1,368). In the
    same year, CIN having one of the lowest number of wins managed to have more
    hits than STL. This furthers the strengthening of the fact that a strong
    offense doesn’t necessarily make teams win, rather both a strong defense
    coupled with a strong offense will better their chances.
</p>
<p>
    <img
        width="624"
        height="315"
        src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image016.jpg"
        alt="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/2xpj4Vwqh8Nr10IgYqONC_PnMwWkK-hO0x9-kR7XqZm4KZKGt1cCOrmOy9Fec0HhqOkaoQRdW1e7wVvy3oCuLyqkIvR--ZKoFEFb_7SrmOscb1UdpR27WO0Bd8d3RzK6LEtwb68c"
    />
</p>
<p>
    Getting more runs than the other team is how you win in a game of baseball,
    one method to achieve that is to prevent the other team from scoring. The
    stats that were analyzed for the defense of the MLB teams include
    regression analysis of Hits allowed vs Wins, Runs allowed vs Wins, and Runs
    Earned vs Wins. Comparing the three based from R-squared shows that the
    strongest is the Runs Allowed vs Wins. This analysis makes sense as the
    less runs you give up the more likely you are to win, this applies to both
    teams in the same game though. Some recommendations to make for teams to
    help prevent Runs allowed would include focusing less on pitching and more
    on infield play, devoting extra practice time to preventing the number of
    allowed bases per hit, and to focus on preventing steals and walks.
</p>
<p>
    While the prevention of hits is important to preventing overall scores, the
    likelihood of a no-hit game based off the data we had would be 0.25%.
    Therefore, teams shouldn’t be focusing on allowing no hits during a game,
    but rather to prevent the players that do hit from scoring. This can be
    achieved by focusing less on pitching perfect games and more on the infield
    and outfield play. The number of runs could potentially be greatly cut down
    if teams increase the time and money spent on their training of inner field
    play, as well as outfield play. With that said, improved pitching is still
    a great benefactor for increased wins for a team. Another key point to
    focus on rather than keeping down runs is to prevent the runner from making
    it past first base. Lastly, the number of hits doesn’t include walks, but
    walks can lead to scores depending on other hits and steals from the team.
    While a team might not strike out, the number of players aiming to score
    can be cut down by the prevention of walks.
</p>
<p>
    In reference to the graph below, you can see that the defensive variables
    (Hits allowed, Runs Allowed, Earned Runs) are incredibly important for
    increasing wins for MLB teams. The top 3 teams based on wins had on average
    200 less hits, allowed as well as 200 less runs throughout the season.
</p>
<p>
    <img
        width="625"
        height="328"
        src="file:///C:/Users/kylea/AppData/Local/Temp/msohtmlclip1/01/clip_image018.jpg"
        alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RyKWmBzf3yta3qnqm9OKRt7JLdy4s9zB57Asa0YMxZRzlyCz27Fglrn2nAZDR_THl7OF-USohOHu0Biuz6gDQ5EyzXJ7YaeGoKNyEa9YuRyhdK-cCfjSdp2MexRoIHe4Nr4dlsEm"
    />
</p>
<p>
    While winning is the most important statistic for the team, revenue is the
    most important aspect for the owners of the teams. A big contribution
    towards revenue is brought in by the game tickets, concessions, and on-site
    merchandise. The amount of revenue brought in is affected by the number of
    fans attending the games throughout the season. While most of the research
    and analysis completed was focused on how teams are more likely to earn
    wins. There was also regression analysis done on whether attendance
    affected the number of wins. The R-squared at a mere 0.19 showed that there
    wasn’t a strong linear regression between the two variables. This means
    that getting more wins throughout the season doesn’t guarantee of increased
    attendance. The in-game statistics do not have a correlation with
    attendance, so instead, companies should focus more on advertisement,
    offering discounts or deals, or to expand on the number of seats if they’re
    reaching capacity to ensure more seats are available for fans.
</p>
<p align="left">
    <strong>Conclusion:</strong>
    <strong><u></u></strong>
</p>
<p>
    An initial analysis of the set of MLB data found that Wins were normally
    distributed with a slight positive skew and wide degree of dispersion,
    mean, standard deviation, and variance that showed to differ from year to
    year. A thorough analysis of the data set allowed us to determine impactors
    for our dependent variable (wins) from the selected independent variables
    (Hits, Hits Allowed, Runs Allowed, Earned Runs, and Attendance). The
    analysis showed that the variables that lead towards runs (Hits, 1B, 2B,
    3B, Home runs, etc.) were not as statistically correlated to getting wins
    as the variables that lead to preventing runs (Hits Allowed, Runs Allowed,
    Earned Runs). For this process, the data was utilized through a linear
    regression within Excel to find trend lines, R-squared, and p-values.
    Utilizing these statistical measures allowed linear regression hypothesis
    testing that demonstrated when either a linear or a non-linear relationship
    existed. This process allowed analysis and observances of possible
    correlations between wins and our independent variables. Utilizing our
    regression models and hypotheses testing allowed our group to determine
    that the defensive variables such as hits allowed, runs allowed, and earned
    runs allowed would have a great effect on wins while discontinuing our
    statistical analysis on offensive stats due to conclusive evidence for lack
    of correlation. Since the offensive variables aren’t as correlated to wins
    as the defensive variables, our recommendations leaned more towards
    defensive options. Teams should focus more on defensive strategies such as
    earned runs, runs allowed, hits allowed, and prevention since these have
    more of an impact on their chances of winning. This doesn’t mean that teams
    should completely stop working on hitting and running, but these additional
    resources shouldn’t be their main priority to their current routine. At the
    very basic level, teams should focus more on preventing runs first and
    preventing hits second. There are several ways to prevent these, including
    focusing on infield play, fly ball catches, preventing walks, and limiting
    the number of bases earned by hits.
</p>
<p>
    Team owners have two primary areas to focus on, their teams getting wins,
    and making money. We have already covered what to do to achieve more wins,
    but how can an owner make their team more profitable. A statistic provided
    by our data set included the yearly attendance for each team. Through
    analysis we found that the R-squared for attendance vs wins was weak at
    .19. If a team’s winning does not improve the attendance, then what would?
    We recommended that team owners focus on either improving the amount made
    during a ballgame by concessions and merchandise sales or to focus on
    outside factors to draw a larger crowd.
</p>
